# **VIVEKA K**

**(** (+91) 94870 03419 **≥** viveka2613@gmail.com

🗘 viveka-k in viveka-k 🔗 viveka-k.github.io

#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

A software engineering graduate with 1 year of experience in software development looking for an opportunity to work in a challenging organization to utilize my knowledge and skills while contributing to the growth of the company.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## MiQ Digital India Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru

# Software Engineer Intern | Dec 2021-June 2022

- Developed dynamic and interactive web application using React.
- Worked with senior developers to test product features and functions and wrote 15+ test cases.
- Assisted as a secondary manager during scrum meetings and provided support for the platform.
- Responsible for participating and driving effective scrum ceremonies including daily scrum, backlog grooming, sprint planning, reviews and retrospectives.

## Takvaviya Analytics Pvt Ltd, Chennai

# Front-End Developer Intern | May 2020-Nov 2020

- Developed user interfaces using frameworks such as Angular and Bootstrap which improved user satisfaction by 30%.
- Worked on a critical project for the company with 100% on-time delivery.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.

# PROJECTS -

# Project Tracking Software - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, MySQL

• The project tracking software is used to manage a project by keeping track of the tasks.

## Distance Matrix Routing App - React, TomTom Map API

• The distance matrix routing app is used to find the shortest route and traffic on the roads.

# Zenuine India - React, NodeJs, Express, MongoDB, Stripe

• Zenuine India is an E-commerce website for a clothing store.

## JusTalk - React, Agora API

• JusTalk is a video calling application used for making group video calls.

# **EDUCATION**

# Coimbatore Institute of Technology | 2017-2022

MSc Software Systems(Integrated) **CGPA**: 8.48/10

## SKILLS -

• C, C++, Python, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, React, Angular, MySQL

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) from Coursera.
- Machine Learning with Python from Coursera.
- Full-Stack Web Development with React Specialization from Coursera.